hello everybody welcome back to
hermitcraft now
this is a secret okay but you remember
last episode that was like only
yesterday
mumbo was afk you see that you see that
in the tab list well it's been like 12
hours
and he's still afk he's been there
overnight he's still in that little box
over there and you remember that i gave
him a trident because he lost one of his
and i said how that was such a good deed
that i did
well
i need to mess with him now there's no
such thing as a free lunch i'm gonna
enlist the help of somebody and we're
going to really mess with him
so i've told this girl yo scout come and
meet me at my base and bring the
obsidian that i asked for now even
though that there's obsidian involved in
this
you need to understand the lengths that
i'm going to go to to make sure that
mumbo has a very bad first five minutes
of his next episode
this is going to be absolutely hilarious
let's just wait for a scout to get here
oh there he is
oh hey iskall
what your man what was going on why did
they say run
i don't know i hope that they didn't
mean anything because i'm scared
this is a trap you asked me to bring
obsidian last time i was here i remember
falling into
a pit
and yeah
oh i remember that
no this isn't for you this is for our
mustached friend okay
oh okay yes so
come come with me it's better to show
you what he's done to himself and then
you can understand where i'm coming from
what he's done happens so rarely on this
server that we have to do something and
i don't feel bad about what we're going
to do because i gave him a free trident
and as everybody knows there's no such
thing as a free lunch right
so
this is this is the this is the thing
that makes it okay right
so over here we have our flying mumbo
jumbo leo
wait oh my goodness
is he okay he's afk dude but what he's
done
is he's taken off all of his gear and
put it in that chest because
because last time he was afk in here he
died and lost everything because phantom
spawned so just to be on the safe side
he's removed his everything
and green the master asks me to bring
obsidian i i i connect the dots right
now right
the the planets have aligned
and it is time to pull a prank on mumbo
mm-hmm i'm pretty sure
i'm pretty sure you me and the audience
know what we're gonna do now
yes i better take my hat off for this
one yeah yeah me too i'm gonna take my
hat off
i better i better put my put my good
face on as well well all right i'm not
gonna put on
my one because
what i've also got here
is a curse of binding
green head and we're gonna
we're gonna dispense this on his face
so yes there's so many layers to this
we're gonna take this so over the top
that he's going to he's gonna log back
in right well no he's gonna come back to
his computer and he's gonna be like wait
what's this so he's gonna see
that he's got loads of green heads in
there you see that chest that's where
the trident is and the trident has been
renamed to the fork of friendship okay
and then he's going to realize why am i
in a cobblestone box and then he's going
to realize he's got a curse of binding
hat on him
and then he's going to realize he's
stuck his items have gone and then he's
going to realize he's stuck in obsidian
this is going to be absolutely hilarious
it's going to be good yep yep let's do
this okay
i have myself plenty of obsidian to do
this we need i think we need to make the
box kind of big enough wait wait wait
does he have his electron
he doesn't have oh he does have his
elytra on oh no have my plans been
scuppered
i bet he has got his stuff on him
why would he do that though why would he
place a chest and keep his pickaxe on
him
i don't know
i say we go ahead with it
i mean this is a weird assortment of
things that he's got in here
it is it feels like he's just okay my
logic here is that because he died he's
created
this chest so that he can dump his items
and just in case it happens again so it
doesn't make sense if he
has
everything you know it doesn't make
sense uh i i say i say we go ahead with
it bro yep let's commit to this and then
if he has got his pickaxe it won't be as
funny
we're gonna make this obsidian box just
a little bit bigger than this
cobblestone box
so he gets the sense of achievement from
falling down the block when he breaks
the cobblestone
oh man okay have you got have you got
some
uh the materials that i asked you to
bring some pink dye
i have pink thigh yes times two
i have obsidian i'm gonna dispense i'll
wait for you but i'm gonna dispense this
so i've got a green head and it's called
together forever
what is wrong with you i said dude i
don't know what is wrong with you
many many things i just i feel like i
can't be like good or evil i have to be
neutral but because i gave him like a
trident and i helped him with the
creeper farm i feel like i just i've the
balance of nature has been
uh tossed a strewn you know i have to i
have to restore the balance
do you want to see do you want to see
this cursor binding head go on him i
want i do i do what is wrong with this
hold on right you're ready so he's
together forever in there
ready
[Laughter]
got him
[Music]
why is messing with mumbo so much fun
this is crazy dude this is five and a
half stacks of obsidian yeah i didn't
think this through very much very much
okay i've just confirmed that in this
chest here he's got all of this stuff
still here like two elytra
four diamond swords for some reason but
he's got a subscribe pickaxe here i
think he's left his stuff here you know
i'm gonna rename this pickaxe salvation
salvation
where are you gonna put it
he's not getting it for free i hope no
what we're gonna do is
we're gonna put this we're gonna put
this
pickaxe in a chest and cover that chest
with obsidian
so even
goes for that first so yeah basically
we're going to put a sign saying because
right this is how i picture it playing
out he's going to log in he's going to
go through all that stuff finding the
trident etc and he's going to try and
escape and he's going to try and dig
down he's going to dig through the
cobblestone and then he's going to fall
down into that little area that we've
made right yes yes and then we leave a
sign that says salvation lies inside and
we're going to put the chest the pickaxe
inside the chest so it doesn't matter
what he does really he could punch a
hole through the obsidian downwards or
he could punch a
an obsidian above the chest it it makes
no difference to me but he's he's got to
do it he ha yeah he has to punch
obsidium basically
what was that oh let's go let's go
oh no no no no is he safe down there is
he safe yeah he's safe he's safe he's
safe
does it work on the head level to do
this i don't even know well does anyone
wait to find out
there we go nice yeah
oh my goodness beautiful he's gonna put
he's gonna like connect all of these
dots together i've made an entrance for
us
what a graceful
graceful fall
[Laughter]
all right
so the theory is he's going to log in
he's going to find out all this stuff
and we need to
put in some chests so we'll put like
that maybe
yep
okay so i'm going to put salvation in
the top left one
that one there we'll put sorry not this
one and then i'll put subscribe to
iskall right here okay and then i'll put
subscribe to green here
and we are thinking a like here so i'm
gonna do this
yep
we need to
hold on and then i'll write this sign
here
right there we go so this is how i see
it plan it panning out okay
so he logs in or he comes back he sees
in front of him
a bunch of my green heads and a chest he
opens the chest and he sees the fork of
friendship and he's like ah that's nice
and then he checks his inventory and he
sees
he's wearing some trousers that say
what'd they say
it's scandinavian trousers
trousers
and a green head on his face that says
together forever
he then starts to panic about why he's
covered in cobblestone
and then
and then he starts to break down now if
he does have a pickaxe this is all
broken already it doesn't work but it's
still funny
but if he doesn't have a pickaxe he's
gonna punch through the cobblestone and
fall down here and he's gonna be like
what the heck
and then he's gonna see these signs
and then he's gonna have to either break
through this obsidian here to get in the
chest or he's going to break through and
fall down the bottom but he doesn't know
how thick we made this exactly the
smartest thing is always always like
you know do what what you think is right
do what the science say do what the
signs say that that's the golden rule of
minecraft the person doesn't know that
doesn't know how to play the game
obviously hold on i need to i need to
check one thing
what's the yeah there there are some
blocks in here so i'm going to remove
the blocks and the chests anything that
he can pillar up with so that the
natural way will go to be to go down
because if he would have blocks he may
have thought like going upwards
let's just take all of this stuff you
know let's just we'll put this
i'll put i'll put a green head in there
oh and then and the chest plate look at
that
oh do you think he has food by the way
because otherwise he will die oh
okay hold on subscribe
mambo style here
this is silly
we're both just renaming everything in
here
oh
what have you done you've done subscribe
i've done sorry not sorry and this is
the price of a free trident
yeah this is this is epic okay this is
beautiful all right i think i think
we're officially done here i think we
could call it a day
our work is done hopefully mumbo will
learn his lesson not to go afk while um
while we're in other people wants to
play on the server yeah he's not allowed
to play hermitcraft anymore no
gg oh my goodness
i'm glad i had some help here cause
otherwise this would have taken ages
thank you so much
thank you as well
yeah i can't oh wait to see this
he's either gonna take this really well
or really badly either way it's all in
good fun mumbo's not gonna be angry not
too angry anyway
yeah
he's not going to lose his mustache no
well hmm
whoa why why are there so many
they are piling in that was really good
fun and the punishment that mumbo had to
endure was only about four minutes ten
now it's actually the next day from
recording and mumbo has actually left he
is
afk again can you believe it i cannot
wait to see his reaction because
well if we go and have a look
he has escaped wait there's he's removed
everything he removed all of that
obsidian okay now i feel kind of bad
wait no wait a minute
ah no there was nothing in there i'm
pretty sure there's nothing oh no
oh i wasn't flying
oh i totally deserved that
this is why i keep backup elytra on me
okay let's go and pick up all of our
stuff
[Laughter]
whoops
i'm meant to be good at flying remember
so anyway mumbo has escaped he's got rid
of all the obsidian i cannot wait to see
what that looked like i think he's now
afk over here instead
yep there he is
i suppose he's got to go afk so that all
of his farms can run off i wonder what
he did with the curse of binding stuff
look he's that he's got all of his gear
and he he keeps up
did he move
oh he's there
uh
he he could totally see me there's some
funny business i knows it
um
it wasn't me
it was the man in the chicken costume
oh dear
[Laughter]
he's he must like have some sort of
security system now he must have like
his sound on so that he can hear if
anyone starts messing with him
okay well we won't we won't pull the
same prank twice
but that is very very funny and i also
got some more gem donations which has
resulted in even more player heads
and you guys are so clever or well
you're either very clever or i'm just
bad at making riddles because
well you guys sussed out my riddles very
quickly
and so have the hermits they've gone so
let me take you through them and so that
i can tell you
so this green head riddle is inside the
spherical bone that lives redstone you
will need to go inside the cutlery that
sits above the plate with pride
all right
so that one is done now what that was
is
the spherical bone which is a skull and
it hides redstone but that could be
anyone that could be tango but then the
cutlery that you typically place above a
plate is the spoon meaning
inside mumbo's head
is where all the green heads were
and then he's got a tiny little brain in
here but tango found it first sorry you
were beaten don't go losing your head
over it so yeah tango found this one
fair and square
so that was riddle number one found
fairly easily
now riddle number two was meant to be
the harder one but that's the one that's
everyone seemed to get instantly
from night to day but never day to night
seek beneath the tower of fright now
most of you got that that was the tag
tower because you're scared of being
tagged so well done to everyone
and from day to night or well from night
to day but not never day to night that
means a bed so if we go over to the tag
tower
there is a bed right here so if you can
work out that it's bed plus tag tower
dig down
you get yourself the green head prize
no i don't know who found this one
probably tango but i think those were
pretty good riddles if i do say so
myself but obviously not good enough
because
they were found so quickly but because
we have a bunch more green heads and
everyone seemed to have a lot of fun
trying to work out my riddles i'm gonna
try and do a couple more while we're
here
i just need to find a suitable place
man that i thought those riddles might
last a little longer than that so
yeah i'm gonna have to think about this
and i should also just place some heads
around as well
so that i can keep the game going they
don't necessarily have to be too hidden
and i've even put a load of them exactly
where
the heads were before but the green head
hunt has actually been really
interesting i'm just hoping to see a
bunch more well green head wars going on
i want to see people stealing some stuff
you know i want to see people taking
green heads from other players in really
creative ways so in an undetermined
location meaning that you guys don't
know where it is either i have placed 20
green heads i don't want to place too
many in case my riddles are really far
too easy to get so i'm now going to
write a new one i don't think i'm very
good at making riddles this might be far
too easy but hear this out and see if
you can figure it out the green head
riddle neither white nor black this
thing takes flight seek inside
the soft ins that i just write it inside
with inside let me try that again
okay it doesn't rhyme but it sounds
better than the last one
neither white nor black this thing takes
flight seek within the soft inside uh
that kind of it sounds nice we'll go and
do another one now i just need to go and
find a location and then come up with a
riddle
sometimes there's also fantastic
opportunities like this
where i can create passengers
for planes and such
how funny does that look anyone flying
by is gonna see all this
now i don't want to put too many in here
because that's a lot of green heads but
i think that's pretty funny okay let's
go and find a location
all right so i've picked down another
place and i just spent about
10 minutes trying to figure out how to
make this riddle work and again i think
it's too easy i
it's meant to be fun and it's also meant
to be possible
i'm really not cut out for this job but
everyone seems to really enjoy it okay
let me read this one again for you
green head riddle to the limit you must
go travel yonder to the color of snow
stand in the middle and you will fall
that which has two but never three drop
down to green heads 33
now
i hope that that's good enough it um
it's not the perfect riddle but it gives
enough clues to work out what it is and
that's the main thing now if they find
those clues super quickly i'm just gonna
have to come up with something so
difficult and
obscure
that it just it just gets found that's
what i'm gonna have to do but i think
those were probably too easy i'll kind
of get an idea if you guys can figure it
out just like that and well i suppose
you guys know a lot more about the
hermitcraft server than i do in some
regards so it'd be interesting to see
right so let's crack on shall we
oh
whoa
uh that the higher this building gets
i'm kind of grateful that it can't get
any taller because
if it did i
probably just keep falling in my base
all the time now last episode i said
that we would continue with this time
lapse down here in the cave now
unfortunately i haven't had time to do
that
but i'm going to continue this in my
spare time because it is pivotal that
this gets done it's just unfortunately
quite a boring project to work on
just placing stone all the time is just
a little bit on the dull side
unfortunately
i just wish making a cave was a bit more
fun
maybe i could employ the help of scar
here to help speed up the process but
i'm sure scar's got his own projects to
work on and anyway this is meant to be a
big secret even though i'm showing you
guys
at least is a little bit safer in here
so we'll leave this for now this will be
ticking away in the background
but one thing is for sure we need an
entrance to it
and that's going to be a bit of an issue
because there's a layer of water between
my base and this but i kind of want it
to drop down roughly in the center here
so if i take this
and i
tower up we can work out roughly where
we want this to go
and i'm going to need to do a bit of
redstone pistonry to try and get through
here
oh that's oh that's right on the beacon
that is uh that's actually rather
unfortunate
we need to think about this carefully
and this is such an awkward place like
there's there's like an aquarium
underneath my base still that i just
haven't taken care of
actually the way that this is at the
moment
this actually looks like it could be the
center if actually if i just moved
across a few blocks that direction this
could easily be the center meaning i can
work around my beacon problem
and i can have an entrance
into the center of this
now i did say that i was going to keep
the purpose of this a secret but again
you guys are so clever and have already
kind of worked out what this might be
for
so i'm guessing we'll keep this as the
main entrance but i want to show you how
i plan
on making this entrance so i plan on
hiding this as a trident wall now i did
say before that i would show you i
showed you the whole pressure plate
thing that when you throw the trident it
activates the pressure plate but i got
an email from someone called jay and
they showed me a new technique for this
that's absolutely genius they obviously
had been playing with the trident just
like i had in trying to make a new
system for it and they figured out that
you can detect a trident through a wall
in a much better way than i had been
doing so this is what we do
you place a bunch of tripwire hooks like
this behind a wall and then of course
link them up with some string so it's
already not exactly a cheap mechanism
but it's genius
now just to show the fact that there's
an output i'll put some redstone lamps
here so i've set up the wall here now
there's a thing that a trident does when
it returns to you
it pauses for a second but then it kind
of glitches to the other side now this
is an entity so if i throw it here it
passes through as you can see
just for a second before it comes back
to me
if i throw this in theory at this wall
there we go if i throw this at the wall
it passes through to the other side and
it hits the string on the other side
triggering the redstone now that is
amazing all i need to do is throw this
red this trident at any part of the wall
now unfortunately it's not a hundred
percent reliable but most of the time
you throw it at the wall
it will activate the the string behind
it and you get a signal it is kind of
annoying that it's not a hundred percent
of the time i'm not sure what i'm doing
differently maybe it's just because i'm
hitting kind of between blocks but if i
throw it out there it yeah i think the
trick here is to throw in between two
blocks but i'm still just throwing it at
the wall so it's very much the same
principle as my trident locked door
before but this time
there's a lot more freedom with throwing
against the wall and also there's a lot
more chance of someone just randomly
throwing a trident at you one of your
walls and setting it off so this is
really really clever back here all it's
a very simple mechanism but the trident
activates it so
easily
so anyway that's basically what i plan
on doing to open up this cave
down beneath us somewhere
and i'm hoping that there will be a good
wall to do it on so maybe like over here
so i'll just throw the trident over
there it'll trigger open up a hole down
there and down i go if anyone has a
smarter way to do this or some other
method that is way better than this one
then please please please go ahead and
let me know
what is x doing here
can i help you excuse you
can i help you
what's what's he doing i'm not sure what
x is up to
well there he goes i'm not sure what's
going on here i just hope that he
doesn't go down here that's the main
thing as long as he doesn't go down into
the infinity room i think we're okay
while zuma
prances around my base this might be a
good opportunity to tell all of you
about the new nether hub design so if i
press tab for a second you can see
there's some rather large numbers next
to people's names
now this counts how many
nether quartz or blocks i think possibly
that you break in the nether here
because we are making a huge and i mean
huge
minimap of the entire server i think
zoomer probably explained it the best on
his video but basically you see this
like dark outline here that's the border
of what we're going to be working on and
we need to clear out all of this
netherrack which is a serious task so
it's going to take a lot of time i've
already committed quite a lot of
resources to this project but i don't
actually want to build too much of it
but i'm quite happy to help try and
clear out as much as possible i'll make
some contributions oh no he can't go in
the he wants to go in the infinity room
uh
uh i need to stop him there's there's uh
there's the incriminating evidence in
there
oh no he's gonna find it
you can't you can't go in there right
now uh you know it's occupied x
okay he i think he kind of knows where
it is but not
not truly nowhere it knows where it is
i don't know don't go in there
don't no
no oh no no no no
no okay x um look it's not what it looks
like
now how did that how did that get there
it did
and now
who on earth keeps this it keeps a
costume down here like
what on earth
and uh
no it's uh nothing to do with me uh why
don't why don't you just uh
uh come on out of there now ex come on
come along now come on out someone has
gone and put a chicken costume in my
infinity room
ah
now wha why would someone do that oh so
x is looking for the green heads but he
can't figure out the riddle
oh this is brilliant i need to go and
read it again to make sure that it
actually makes sense because i'll be
honest with you guys he got very very
close there but he didn't quite get the
get get it there so let me just check if
he's got it head to the limit you must
go travel yonder to the color of snow
stand in the middle and you will fall
that witch has two but never three
dropped down to green heads 33. no that
makes sense no it actually does make
sense he got very close but not close
enough
you know he no i agree with i i i have
made a really good riddle that is going
to lead people around my base but
they're not actually going to find it so
yes the green heads are in my base but
the riddle is actually really good you
have to take each part of it into
consideration
okay
well um someone's gone and put a chicken
costume in my base which is
it must have been the man in the chicken
costume he must be keeping his stuff in
my base which is absolutely absurd
so yeah that was the nether hub thing
going on that we're gonna be
we're gonna be taking out a lot of that
netherrack
but i'm afraid that is it from me for
today everybody i do appreciate you guys
watching ever so much the last episode
of hermitcraft was actually on the
trending page for gaming i've never had
a trending video in my life so that is
very very exciting and i want to thank
each and every one of you for your
continued
daily support of this series it actually
makes me
incredibly humbled so thank you so much
for not just watching this video but
watching all of these hermitcraft videos
it's it's been an absolute blast and i
can't wait to keep going because i have
so many ideas and i want to keep making
some brilliant episodes for you that are
equally goofy and fun to watch so thank
you very much everyone and i'm going to
continue mining netherrack forevermore
goodbye